[dramatic music playing]
[alarms blaring]
- [people clamoring]
- We need to get her out of there!
[Hank] Stop!
The poison could still be inside.
- [grunting]
- Knox! Stop!
- Listen to me.
- [Shirley] Hey!
We all wanna save her. Okay.
we all wanna save her. but if you open
this door. we have no...
- Ow. God! Ow! Please. No!
- [Shirley] Everybody. stop!
- [Hank] We all wanna save her.
- [Teddy] It's stopped!
- Knox. you gotta think--
- The fire stopped!
- [breathes rapidly]
- [clamoring stops]
- We need to open the door.
- No. no. no. no.
No one's ever gone in before.
The lock doesn't release
- for 48 hours after a cleaning.
- She's... She's...
- Forty-eight hours after--
- Juliette's moving!
[tense music playing]
Fuck 48 hours.
Clear the cafeteria.
We're opening the door.
[Knox grunts]
- [Knox] Move!
- [Shirley grunts]
- [Knox grunting]
- [door creaks]
[groans]
Come on!
[all grunting]
- [Knox] Go get the straps. You get her.
- [Teddy] Come on.
[Shirley panting]
- [Knox] Easy. Easy.
- [Shirley] Get her down.
When she's out.
we'll wrap it right around.
[Knox. Shirley panting]
- [grunts]
- [Shirley] Careful.
[panting] Easy. Shirl. Shirl. Be careful.
Hank! Hank!
Get in here. I need help!
[Hank] Come on. guys.
Come on. Let's go. Go!
Teddy. they're coming!
- [Shirley] Move! Clear the way!
- [Paul] Move 'em back!
[Hank] Get back. Out of the way!
Make some room! Go!
[Shirley] Clear out! Move!
Back it up! Let's go!
[Paul] Move 'em back! Get back!
- [Hank] Let's go!
- [Paul] Get back!
We're going up the stairs. Watch it.
Stay with me. Stay with me.
Come on. Please get out of the way!
Move back! Move!
Go! Back. please stand back. Stand back.
[grunting. clamoring]
- [engineer 1] Get ready.
- [engineer 2] Come on.
[grunts]
Get those ropes up.
Come on. Move! Move.
- [Paul] Hold.
- [Knox] Pull.
[Hank] Nice and easy.
Hey!
[residents] ♪ Hear the bell that rings ♪
♪ It's calling us ♪
♪ To our duty ♪
[Kennedy] Move.
♪ Hear the voices sing ♪
♪ So loud and proud ♪
[Bernard] I was told...
♪ Praise freedom's beauty ♪
...the entire Silo was watching
as we were being lowered down.
But what...
Everyone thinks you're dead...
so how did you end up down here?
[Sims] How the fuck do you think?
[dramatic music playing]
[The Algorithm] Judge Sims.
you and your son must leave the vault.
Camille can stay.
[somber music playing]
[Camille whispering] What?
[Sims breathing shakily]
[whispering] It's okay.
[door locks]
[Anthony] Dad?
Everything is okay.
[exhales sharply] Mom is safe
and now we're gonna find
a safe place for you and me.
- [Anthony breathes shakily]
- Okay?
[door opens]
[tense music playing]
[door closes]
[keys jingling]
Are you okay?
- Is Anthony--
- He's asleep. Finally.
I can't stay long.
But I needed to see you.
What?
What happened in the vault
after we left you?
[inhales sharply] Rob. I...
I can't talk about that.
What do you mean
you can't talk about that?
Okay...
Did Bernard ever tell you
about what happened in that room?
Or-Or what the voice was?
Or even that there was a voice?
I knew he got instructions in there.
But I didn't know how.
And you won't tell me?
If I could...
Uh. we came straight here.
I haven't been out.
- I have no idea what's going on.
- It's calm.
Bernard and Juliette came back inside.
Inside?
- How?
- They survived the fire. Barely.
Did the poison get in?
It doesn't look like.
Did anyone try to open the door?
No.
Rob. the rebellion was over the second
she appeared over the top of the hill.
But there are still threats to the Silo.
- Who?
- Bernard Holland.
Lukas Kyle.
And Juliette Nichols.
[chuckles]
A-Are you asking me to take care of it?
I'm telling you there's a problem.
And we both know
this isn't the first time the head of IT...
- I'll take care of it. okay?
- ...has asked you to handle
a problem for them.
[ominous music playing]
What's the concern?
They know things
that could threaten the Silo.
Things I can't know.
That's what you're telling me.
What's the order of priority?
Lukas Kyle is the lowest.
When you find him. just make sure
- he doesn't speak to anyone.
- Gag and bag.
- Yes.
- Mm-hmm.
Juliette and Bernard
are the greatest threat.
Of the two?
Whoever seems likely to talk first.
[doctor] Honestly. it's too early to tell.
[Sims] Either of them say anything?
Uh. Juliette Nichols is unconscious.
Bernard Holland has made sounds.
not words.
Pain response. He's badly burned.
Nichols?
That suit she was wearing protected her.
Holland's had a lot of burn-through.
Nichols has some burns where the metal
in her collar and wristbands heated up.
And what's your plan
if they don't make it?
We don't have a protocol for any of this.
but I had plastic sheeting
and remains bags placed in their rooms.
I don't believe traditional burial
would be safe. The poison--
- Incineration then.
- Yes.
But the incinerator's 140 levels down.
And if the bodies are contaminated.
and I would have to assume they are.
they'll have to be wrapped in plastic
before being put in the bags.
Protective suits for the porters.
Clear the stairs.
It won't be easy.
Then let's hope they live.
[Bernard breathing heavily]
[Bernard straining]
[hoarsely] Robert.
I... I know the voice wants me dead
but... [inhales deeply. gulps] I... [sputters]
[sinister music playing]
- [winces]
- [breathing heavily]
[rasps. whimpers]
[whimpering. groaning]
[groaning continues]
[breathing heavily]
They can k-kill us at any time.
[panting]
The whole Silo.
That's what Lukas Kyle found out.
What he told me.
But Juliette...
Juliette knows how to stop it.
[groaning]
[dramatic music playing]
[grunting]
[gasps. inhales deeply]
[grunts. coughs]
[breathing heavily]
- Nice outfit.
- I have a job for you.
- [electricity crackling]
- You sure you don't wanna go up top?
Be near Medical?
[Martha] I'm not a doctor.
I can't do anything for her.
Now. down here though.
there's plenty to keep me busy.
Well. there better be
an apartment for us in Mechanical.
because I am not sleeping
in this shithole.
Are you staying?
- I was thinking about it.
- [door opens]
- I need your help.
- [Martha] Yeah. and what makes you think
- we'd lift a finger?
- We hate you.
Because my wife is the new head of IT.
and she wants Juliette Nichols dead.
Now. if you help me.
we can stop that from happening.
- You're going against your own wife?
- In five minutes.
I'm meeting with a group of porters
in the incinerator room.
Once they leave.
I have to make a body disappear.
and I need your help to do it.
The Silo has to believe
this person is dead.
Meet me there.
Or don't.
But Juliette's life is on the line.
Who-Who-Who do you want disappeared?
[suspenseful music playing]
[door closes]
How the fuck are you smiling
after all that?
[hoarsely] It's the drugs you gave me.
[door opens]
Our help comes with a condition.
If anything happens to our girl.
we tell Camille that you betrayed her.
And we toss Holland
into the incinerator for real.
- Then let's get moving.
- [Carla] Hold on.
How can you be so certain
that your wife won't just handle Juliette
while you're down here with us?
Because I made sure
Juliette Nichols is unkillable.
[people speaking indistinctly]
What's going on? Any news yet?
Why were the stairs closed?
The poison got one of them.
They said it wasn't Juliette.
It was Holland.
Had to take him to the incinerator.
If Bernard Holland is dead.
then who's mayor?
What?
Who's mayor?
We need a mayor. don't we?
- [resident] Yeah.
- Yeah.
And if we don't choose someone.
then know they'll choose for us.
So. who?
We just had a rebellion. [scoffs]
We need someone we can trust
in charge. right?
[all] Yes.
How about someone
who went out and came back?
[person] Yeah. That's right. That's right.
Hell. I say Juliette Nichols
for mayor. Yeah?
- [resident 2] Yeah. Juliette!
- Yeah. Juliette Nichols for mayor!
- [residents] Yeah! Juliette!
- Yeah! Juliette Nichols for mayor!
- Juliette for mayor! Juliette for mayor!
[residents chanting] Juliette for mayor!
Juliette for mayor! Juliette for mayor!
[Bernard speaks hoarsely]
It smells like it's burning.
It's not burning.
[Bernard] Well. you burnt it last time.
[Martha] Yeah. well.
Maybe you're a little sensitive
to things being burnt.
- Did you think of that?
- [Bernard laughs. groans] Ow.
Yeah. I shouldn't be so funny. I'm sorry.
Little hot. still.
You know. I got a question.
All these other silos.
Are they all like ours?
[Bernard] I think so.
So do they all have radios?
They do.
So how come we haven't heard them?
Because you're listening
to the wrong signal.
Bring me a radio
- and I'll show you what I know.
- [door opens]
- Is it done?
- Mayor Juliette Nichols
took the oath of office
from her hospital bed.
They're discharging her this week.
Which means they've started her
on the forgetting drugs.
They need to make sure that
she doesn't remember
what she saw in Silo 17.
If she's on 'em too long.
she'll forget everything.
Then we gotta get her off of those drugs.
[Sims] That's gonna be hard to do.
Camille's got her on a tight leash.
Is there no way of reversing it?
Of. um. getting her memories back?
There's talk in The Order.
What's The Order?
The Order is...
It's like the Pact.
but just for the head of IT
and their shadow.
It gives instructions
on what to do when things go wrong.
When it describes the use
of the forgetting drugs on people.
it says it's essential
to keep them from artifacts
from their past.
as these artifacts can trigger memories.
[Martha] So. that's why you had your goons
looking for relics all of these years.
I never knew about The Order.
But the Pact says a lot
about what's outlawed.
But never said why.
I'd better get started.
Where are you going?
If we're gonna get Nichols off
those drugs.
there's someone I need to see.
Only hope it's not too late.
Baby?
[kisses]
- [kissing continues]
- [cat meows]
[ominous music playing]
[whistling. kisses]
[Sims] You left your door open.
Does this never end?
I need you to get these pills
to Amy Hansen.
She's the nurse attending Mayor Nichols.
Regina. look at me.
I don't know her from a bar of soap.
Why would she take anything from me?
I will send you to an intermediary.
Someone who does know Amy Hansen.
- Who?
- You will tell this intermediary
that at some point
Hansen will need to replace
Nichols's vitamins with these.
What's in those? Poison?
- It's just sugar.
- What's in the pills she's getting now?
It's best if you only know
what you need to know.
Will you do this?
Do I have a choice?
You do.
And what happens if I say no?
My family suddenly get hauled to Judicial?
My friend bumps into a raider
and suddenly goes over the rail?
None of that happens.
- I don't understand.
- I'm just asking if you will help.
[cat meows]
I hear your wife's the new head of IT.
She know about this?
She does not.
Okay.
Now. I'll need you
to start trading in relics again.
I know. I know.
Look. anything that belonged to Nichols.
Raiders and agents.
they will look the other way.
A lot of her stuff's been scooped up
by those women who dress like her.
I'll need something to trade.
Like what?
Something small.
Maybe with her name on it.
Her sheriff's badge.
Ten of them should be enough.
Where did you get the badges?
There's a craftsman in the marketplace
who owed me.
You mean he... he's afraid of you.
Fifty silos. all given the same radio.
Each silo using a different frequency.
What did you say they were called again?
In the book. it calls them channels.
Channels. that's right. channels.
So. I've tuned this radio
to another silo's channel.
so that. in here.
we can talk without anyone hearing.
[Bernard] Silo 1 monitors
all of the active frequencies.
so use it sparingly.
And in code.
Okay. well. ugh.
I gotta go and get some more food.
His appetite's returning.
You headed up soon?
My quarantine doesn't officially end
until noon.
What are you gonna tell your wife?
She told me to take care of
whoever might talk first.
That was you.
You sure you don't want
to get Nichols off the drugs now?
We can't let it happen too soon
after you return from quarantine--
The longer we wait.
- the more difficult it'll become.
- We can't risk losing you. Robert.
You are indispensable.
I'm im-impressed
with how you've handled.
well. everything.
You would have been a great shadow...
but I am glad I didn't give you the job.
Being head of IT...
i-is a brutal.
thankless. impossible task.
It's no better for the shadow.
The things that fucking voice
in the vault made me do.
I thought...
the greatest risk
was from some fool
trying to open the door.
[chuckles]
Camille has it far worse.
They had to tell her about the Safeguard.
and she can't speak about it to anyone.
I imagine...
she's burning alive from the inside.
[Sims] I went back up. and we waited.
Maybe too long
considering how much you forgot.
So when I met you in the pump room.
you were gonna bring me down here?
You were going to talk to me on the radio.
We didn't want anyone coming here.
but you and your friend fucked that up.
That dream you had of you
and Bernard in the air lock.
- Yeah?
- [Sims] That...
That wasn't a dream.
It was a memory.
It happened.
No. no. wait. you...
- Did you... You had a gun?
- Yes.
And you were gonna go out t-to die. right?
Yes.
And then what-what happened?
You happened. Juliette.
I said to you.
"They can kill us all at any time."
And you said. "Maybe not."
What did you mean by maybe not?
I don't remember. I can't.
[Sims] It's okay. we have a plan.
[Lukas grunting]
- [Patrick] Come on. come on. come on.
- [grunts]
The first time I did that.
I just about shit my pants.
How come you're not freaking the fuck out?
What? I am. okay? Just in the mines.
you learn not to show it.
[Kennedy] Yeah. so the big bad bullies
don't pick on you?
[Lukas] No. 'cause there's no point.
Let's go. Come on.
Fifty silos?
Yeah.
- Are they all like us?
- [Martha] Far as I know.
[Knox] But there's one
that can fucking kill us?
Yes.
You've known about this for months.
and you're only telling us now?
I couldn't tell you.
Just like you can't tell anyone.
Listen. we're safe here.
but if anyone speaks about this openly.
then they will kill us.
- [stammers]
- How would that actually happen?
Well. if I knew that.
we wouldn't need Juliette.
- Why would they kill us?
- [Martha] I haven't a clue.
All I know is that they could.
That's all I need to know.
Listen... [inhales sharply]
...the reason I'm telling you this
and scaring the shit out of you
is that I need your help.
Juliette's visit to the digger void
was unanticipated.
so it means
Camille might go down there looking.
and there's something down there
that we can't let her find.
I have to move it. and it's not light.
[Shirley] How much does it weigh?
About 250. and it's a pain in the ass.
You gotta be fucking kidding me?
He's alive?
- You slept there?
- Wouldn't call it sleep.
There's a hostel three levels up.
Everything all right
with your home life. Sheriff?
I told you I needed
to see you immediately.
This is not immediately.
Really?
After all we've been through.
you're gonna play the sheriff card?
It's not a card.
It's a badge.
And yes. I am.
Okay. Paul.
I came as soon as I could.
If Orla isn't here.
then I don't know where she is.
She's in the morgue on 62.
- What?
- She was murdered.
Sorry.
but I need to keep moving on this.
- I have to ask you--
- It's my fault.
It's my fault.
- [Lukas] All right.
- [Patrick] Hey. you know. uh--
Come on. [groans]
Can you. uh. light a match. man?
I-I can't see anything.
Yeah. I just want you to know I don't have
an unlimited supply--
I know you don't have it. I know.
- You-you wanna fall down the shaft?
- No. I don't wanna fall down the shaft.
Okay. Light a match.
Fine. I'm gonna.
When I get to the bottom of the stairs.
I will turn on the light.
All right. good.
- [Patrick yells]
- What the actual fuck!
You need to be very. very quiet.
- [Lukas] Uh-huh. We can. Yes. Yeah.
- [Patrick] We can do that.
[door opens]
[Martha] Wait a minute.
W-Why are they here?
[Sims] They know too much
to be anywhere else.
Do you have the relics?
[clears throat]
[tender music playing]
[chuckles]
[inhales. exhales deeply]
[sniffs]
[music continues]
[inhales. sighs]
[Sims] Anything?
No. I mean. I know. I know...
I know what these things are and I-I...
I recognize them. I just don't...
[Martha] It's okay.
Nothing about how to stop them
from killing us?
I-I-I'm sorry. Who can do what now?
We really need you
to be quiet right now. Please.
You know about the Safeguard then?
- [Sims] Yes.
- Okay.
So. y-you know that they
can kill us at any time?
Yeah. we know that. but I don't know why.
and I can't fucking remember anything.
Okay. um. how is the box supposed to help?
The hope is things from her past
might jump-start her memory.
Right. Okay. Sorry.
Uh. I mean they're toys.
I got everything I could.
What I'm trying to say
is that maybe if we got something
that's more relevant
to when this all started.
Right? Hey. when we met.
yeah. you were asking the big questions:
Why we're here. What it's all for.
But. really.
all you were interested in
was what happened to George.
When I went down
to the bottom of the Silo.
I found a tunnel that led to a door.
and at the door a voice said
that only three people
had ever been there.
Salvador Quinn. Mary Meadows.
and George Wilkins.
[Kennedy] On the hard drive. There was a...
There was a guy who was talking to you.
and Danny said that that guy was George.
Did he say anything
about how to stop the Safeguard?
No. No. He said a bunch of mushy shit.
I don't know.
And then... and then he said something
about... that-that he found a door.
He wanted to find that
door for a long time.
I'm sorry. You also knew George?
- Yeah.
- Well. have you found anything
that belonged to him
that maybe means something to her?
The thing I wanted to get wasn't gettable.
- [Lukas] Why?
- The watch.
George gave you a watch.
[Lukas] I know the watch. [scoffs]
Sorry. Why was it un-gettable?
It was taken from her
before she was sent out to clean.
Bernard gave it to your father.
He was wearing it when
he blew up the stairs.
No. He wasn't wearing it.
He gave it to somebody else.
Y-Your dad wanted me
to give this back to you
if I ever saw you again.
But...
But you weren't really you
when you came back.
- So. I hung on to it.
- [Juliette] Right.
There-There's something...
There's something I gotta tell you. Jules.
What?
- Can... Um...
- They can hear.
[Hank] No. This is just for you.
[Regina clears throat]
- Come over here.
- [Juliette stammers] Yeah.
Um.
He told me to tell you that he loved you.
- He wanted you to keep fighting.
- Mm-mmm.
- And never stop being yourself because...
- Mmm. Okay.
"Because she's perfect.
Exactly as she is."
[ticking]
[George] This must have taken you hours.
[ticking continues]
- [grunts]
- [chuckles]
[somber music playing]
[ticking stops]
George.
Are you okay?
Is there anything else?
Then it's time we head up.
I don't know what we're going to say.
but we've been gone too long.
- Camille's going to--
- Mmm. Did he have anything else? Any...
Do you have anything?
- Not that we know of.
- [Juliette] No?
- Hey. We have to go.
- Mmm.
[Martha] We will keep looking.
[Carla] Critical Supply
can only be accessed
by the head of Supply or their shadow.
[keypad beeping]
[beeps]
[ominous music playing]
Every item that goes out of here
requires three different kinds
of approval.
And the head or their shadow
to be in attendance
when those items are pulled.
Critical Supply contains things
that were loaded in here
when the Silo first began.
The kind of things
that we can't make more of.
That's why it's called critical.
You get what that means?
When we run out. we're out.
Exactly.
Pick up one of those boxes.
- [sighs]
- [Carla] I'll give you a hand.
[Paul grunting]
[grunting continues]
Now. pick up that one.
[Paul grunts]
We keep the empty boxes to stop anyone
who might get in here from doing the math.
The amount of panic it will cause
if. uh. people found out...
Found out what?
How much time we have left.
[Knox] Let's get this shit done.
[Bernard] Miss Campbell. Mr. Knox.
You're gonna pull me up?
Unless we let go.
[groaning]
You're enjoying my discomfort?
For 25 years.
I did what I was told I had to do
- to keep the Silo safe.
- So what? You expect us to forgive you?
For murdering the judge?
Blaming it on us?
Telling the entire Silo to kill us?
N-No. I don't.
I don't.
You both were caught in the middle
of an unfortunate circumstance.
So.
when you pull me up.
I wouldn't be surprised or offended
if you just let me go.
[Bernard groans]
[Bernard whimpering. groaning]
[breathes heavily]
[rustling]
What does this mean?
[sighs]
Twenty years ago
we had 70 years of light bulbs left.
Just before I moved to Mechanical.
about three months ago.
we were down to 50 years.
- Okay. So--
- But a month ago. I did a check.
and I found out that the theft we've been
dealing with in Supply for years
was also happening in Critical Supply.
and that's when I made Orla my shadow.
Because you didn't trust Glenda?
Glenda is capable but prickly.
But Orla. she's from a long line
of Supply-siders.
so I knew I could trust her with the job
and with something else.
You asked her to help you find
who was stealing in Critical Supply.
And you think that's why she got killed?
Carla...
If we can't find those light bulbs.
how long do we have?
With what we got left...
two years.
After that. we won't be able to replace
the ones that go out on the farms.
And when they go. our food goes.
So.
it's only a matter of time
before we die
in the dark.
What do you think Camille is gonna do
when we get there?
I don't know.
Maybe you should put me in handcuffs
and make a scene out of it.
She wanted you dead.
Handcuffs aren't gonna cut it.
Well. you know. one big shove.
and I'll go over the rail.
I mean. we have enough time. right?
[Sims] Nah.
I'm tired.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry.
There's. uh...
Something I gotta tell you. um...
It might not be anything. but. uh...
[breathes shakily] ...since that night
you went into my apartment.
something changed in my boy.
Maybe in me too.
- Okay. Look. I'm sorry. I've-I've said...
- Uh. it's not that.
- I don't know why...
- I didn't bring...
I didn't bring it up for that reason.
And I gave him something.
Told him it'd keep him safe.
And it kinda became our thing.
Ah. like a secret between us.
And the more Bernard talked
about artifacts
being able to trigger someone's memory.
the more I convinced myself that
this thing will help my son remember me...
if Camille released the vitamin D.
Like it was gonna perform
some kind of magic or something.
But it wasn't mine to keep.
It was yours.
George gave it to you.
Was it important?
And in a world filled with a million
unknowns. it is possible that this watch...
- Mm-hmm.
- ...and-- and crazy relics like these...
- George.
- ...are the key to answering
- the Silo's biggest questions.
- George.
[Juliette] ...what's left
of the machine that dug the Silo.
[Bernard]
You would've killed everyone in the Silo.
[Jimmy] What silo? There's 50.
It's a pipe.
- The Safeguard is a pipe.
- [Juliette] Why did they have to cap it?
It had poison in it.
Enough poison to kill everybody.
All 10.000 people.
I remember.
[footsteps running]
There's poison in a pipe.
It comes from outside the Silo.
They capped it in 17.
They fucking capped it.
[Sims] Where does it come in?
I don't know.
I have to talk to the others.
Go.
[hammering. drilling]
[people chattering]
So. I'm at the call center.
and I get a call.
which is weird 'cause I didn't know you
could get incoming calls in that system.
But Sam did two years with the NSA.
- so he knows shit.
- He's got magic beans. Yeah.
What did he say?
Who's the number one advocate
for AI control
who also happens to fund the clinic
where my sister's trying
to rebuild her memory?
- Per Stensen.
- Wanna take a guess
at where Per Stensen was the night
of Operation Righteous Vengeance?
On the Nimitz?
It's usually based in San Diego.
but it's been in Norfolk
since it got back from Iran.
- [sighs]
- Sam knows someone on base
who's willing to talk to us
off the record.
- What-What changed his mind?
- Oh.
I'm guessing Charlotte.
Just knowing what she means to me.
I know Sam.
We didn't just play in a band together.
We got shot at together.
and I've rarely heard him this scared.
Okay. you think all of this
has to do with AI though?
I don't know... [exhales heavily]
...but the other carrier groups that night
sent out 20. 30 sorties.
and the Nimitz sends out one?
With four planes equipped
with pre-digital comms. and then suddenly...
- [engine revs]
- [tires squealing]
Jesus.
- Give me a little warning next time.
- That wasn't me.
- What do you mean?
- I mean it wasn't me.
I'm not driving. Someone else is.
[menacing music playing]